*幸运的家伙*
*A lucky, lucky one*
天呐
Oh, god.
不不不
Oh, no, no, no, no.
露西  我回家了
Lucy, I'm home!
-里克  -你好  亲爱的
- Ricky. - Hello, darling.
露西应该告诉我来客人了的
Lucy, you should have told me we had company.
那得另花钱
That costs extra.
据你的机器朋友说
Well, according to your little, mechanical friend here,
你一直在用冻匹萨发泄悲伤
you have been drowning your sorrows in frozen pizza,
还有网上购物
online shopping...
还连看道夫·龙格尔的电影
And Dolph Lundgren marathons.
你也背叛我  露西
Et tu, Lucy?
没什么隐私可言了吗
Is nothing private?
除非你好好设置我
Not without the proper setting.
亲爱的
Darling, I-I mean,
我知道跟凯瑟琳分开很艰难
I know it's difficult for you without Katherine,
但现在就喝酒是不是早了点
but really, isn't it a little early in the day for this?
这是给莱恩和埃斯波西托的
These are for Ryan and Esposito.
他们今天拿到警长测试结果
They get the results of their sergeant's exam today,
我想稍后去趟分局
So I thought I'd drop down to the precinct,
给他们个惊喜
surprise them a little later on.
如果贝克特恰巧也在
And if Beckett happens to be there...
那就更该庆祝了
All the more reason to celebrate.
考试有结果了吗
Hey, so, any word on the exam?
-别说了  -你要触霉头的
- Stop it. - You're gonna jinx it.
好吧
Okay, okay.
不说了
Done.
蕾妮
Hey, Lanie.
这是谁
So, who is this?
贾斯汀·弗莱彻  38岁
Justin Fletcher, 38.
胸口两处枪伤  近距离开枪
Two GSWs to the chest, close range.
知道案发时间吗
Any idea when this happened?
大概上午10:14左右
Around 10:14 a.m.
好精准啊
That's pretty specific.
911那时接到目击者匿名电话
That's when 911 received an anonymous call from a witness.
技术部正在追踪
Tech's trying to trace it now.
那是被害人的车吗
So that's our victim's car?
是的  钥匙在兜里
Yeah. Keys were in his pocket.
我们在查呢
We're just digging into it.
那就不是劫车了
Then this wasn't a carjacking.
也不是抢劫
Or a robbery.
被害人的钱包现金还在身上
Victim still has cash and wallet on him.
这都是防弹玻璃啊
These are bulletproof windows, huh?
还不止这一点升级呢
That's not the only upgrade.
轮胎是强化防爆轮胎
These tires are reinforced run-flat,
门上装有防弹板
and there are kevlar panels in these doors.
怎么样
So what do you think?
或许是公司安保车
Maybe he was corporate security?
这么小的后座不可能
Not with that tiny backseat.
我是说里面容不下人
I mean, there's no room for a guy to get in there.
-我闭嘴了  -好的吧
- I'm just gonna stop talking. - Yeah, okay.
更加精彩了
Now the plot thickens.
埃斯波  让鉴证组来查查吧
Espo, why don't you get CSU to sweep this?
或许他们能查出被害人藏的什么
Maybe they can tell us what our victim was hiding here.
或许他就因此被杀
Might be what he was killed for.
是考试结果吗
Is that the test results?
不是
No, no.
技术部查到了匿名911电话的姓名住址
Tech got a name and address on that anonymous 911 call.
米娅·拉斯洛
Mia Laszlo.
住在炮台公园
Address in Battery Park.
好了  去找她
All right, pick her up.
谁
Yes?
拉斯洛女士  我是埃斯波西...
Ms. Laszlo, I'm Detective Esposi--
嗯
Yeah.
埃斯波西托警探  这位是莱恩警探
Detective Esposito. This is Detective Ryan.
我们有几个问题想问你
We want to ask you a few questions
是关于你报案的那起凶杀案
about that murder you reported.
-我们可以进来吗  -不行
- Can we come in? - No.
抱歉  女士  我们还是得跟你谈谈
Excuse me, ma'am! We still need to talk to you!
之所以匿名是有原因的
There is a reason it was an anonymous call.
你目睹了凶杀  你要么让我们进去说
You witnessed a murder, so you either let us in to talk,
要么我们押你去警局
or we can drag you down to the station.
等等
Just a minute.
好吧  听清楚  我们这么办
Okay, listen closely. Here's how this is going to go.
我单独坐后座
I ride in the backseat, alone,
窗户要一直开着
and the windows stay down the whole way.
你能想到会有谁
Can you think of anyone
想杀你哥哥吗
who would have wanted to kill your brother?
没有  让人都爱贾斯汀  他是个大好人
No. Everyone loved Justin. He was such a good guy.
我们父母死后  他离开军队来照顾我
He left the army to take care of me after our parents died.
让我上了大学
He made sure that I went to college.
学费都是他付的  尽管他
He, uh... he paid for all of it, even though he...
他一开始老是找不到工作
he had a hard time finding a job at first.
他究竟做什么
And what did he do exactly?
他是高级司机  经常送东西
He was a high-end driver, made a lot of deliveries.
有违法的东西吗
Anything illegal?
我不知道  怎么了
I don't know. Why?
我们在他车上发现了一个秘密隔间
We found a secret compartment in his car,
我们认为他可能
and we think that he might
是因为里面原本装的东西而被杀
have been killed because of what was inside.
你知道他在里面放了什么
Do you have any idea what he kept in there
或者他早上为什么会在那个停车场吗
or maybe what he was doing in the garage this morning?
不知道
No.
我上次跟他通话是昨天
The last time that I spoke to him was yesterday.
他说要去见个叫猎鹰的人
He said that he had to go meet someone named Falcon.
贝克特
Hey, Beckett!
贝克特  贝克特
Beckett, Beckett, Beckett, Beckett, Beckett.
我臭吗
Do I smell?
什么
What?
证人威胁要投诉我
Our witness is threatening to file a complaint against me
说我用致命气味袭击她
for assault with a deadly odor.
说我闻上去像脏尿布
Says that I smell like soiled baby diapers
哈维的古龙水是"撒旦屁股的汗"
and Javi's cologne is "Satan's butt sweat."
是有点浓了  但是
I mean, yeah, it is pretty strong, but...
你去讯问她吧
Can you interview her?
你总是香香的
You always smell so pretty.
警监
Captain.
好吧
Okay, fine.
你和埃斯波查查贾斯汀的生活
You and Espo dig into Justin's life, though,
看能不能找到跟一个叫猎鹰的人的联系
see if you can find a connection to someone named Falcon.
我是贝克特警监
I'm Captain Beckett.
多谢你能来  拉斯洛女士
Thank you so much for coming in, Ms. Laszlo.
我们赶紧说完拉倒吧
Let's just get this over with.
关于早上的凶案  你还记得什么
Uh, so, what do you remember about the murder this morning?
不记得什么了
Not much.
我听到两声枪响
I heard two gunshots,
然后有个带着滑雪面罩的家伙
and then a guy with a ski mask
跟我一起上了电梯
got on the elevator with me.
我以为他要杀我  可他没有
I thought he was gonna kill me, but he didn't.
反而在一楼下了电梯
Instead, he got off at the ground level.
于是我打了911然后离开了
I called 911 and left.
我现在能回家了吗
Can I go home now?
-不行  -为什么
- Uh, no. - Why not?
因为我还...没问完
Because I'm not done asking you questions just...yet.
你早餐总是吃甘蓝菜吗
Do you always eat kale for breakfast?
这可不好
'cause that is just wrong.
你怎么知道我今早吃了甘蓝菜
How did you know that I had kale this morning?
你一身的甘蓝味
You reek of it.
这一屋子都是很烂的希腊菜味儿
Like, this room stinks of grade-"D" greek food.
你鼻子还真灵
You're very sensitive to smell.
你真该改名叫废话警监
Oh, you should change your name to Captain Obvious.
我这叫嗅觉过敏
It's called hyperosmia.
自己查字典
Look it up.
好吧  那凶手有什么味道
Okay, uh, so, what did our killer smell like?
天啊  我说不好
Gosh, I don't know.
要么是宠物狗  要么就是火药味
It was either puppies or gunpowder.
你总是这么凶巴巴的吗
Are you always this unpleasant?
对
Yep.
关于电梯里的那个人
Is there anything else that you remember
你还记得什么吗
about the guy in the elevator?
他是个白人
He was a white guy.
一米八出头  穿着深色衣服
Was about six feet tall, dark clothes,
他还从死者身上抢了个银色公文包
And he was carrying a silver briefcase that he got off of that dead guy.
好  非常感谢
All right. Thank you very much.
主人确认了
Well, the owner confirms it.
停车场没有摄像头
The garage has no cameras.
我已经找人去调看周围区域的监控了
And I got uniforms pulling footage from surrounding areas.
真像台上了油的机器
Like a well-oiled machine.
什么情况
What's that?
考试结果出来了
It's the exam results.
到了揭晓的时刻了
Moment of truth.
是啊
Yep.
好吧  哥们儿  数到三
All right, bro. On three.
1  2
1, 2...
棒
Yes.
埃斯波西托警长在此
Sergeant Esposito right here.
该死  很遗憾  兄弟
Damn. Sorry, bro.
我不明白
I don't understand.
怎么会你通过了而我没有
How did you pass and I didn't?
莱恩  下次吧  好兄弟
Ryan, next time, pal.
埃斯波  好样哒
Espo, way to go!
真棒
Nice.
你懂的
You know.
你好吗
How you doing?
我  还行
I'm, uh, good.
你在电梯那儿稍等会儿好吗
Um, you know, if -- if you just wait by the elevators,
莱恩和埃斯波会送你回家
Ryan and Espo will take you home.
我宁愿去跟尸体舌吻
I'd rather french kiss a corpse.
会有警员载你回去的
A uniform will drive you.
她看起来人不错  鼻子是什么情况
She seems nice. What's with the nose thing?
说来话长
Mm, long story.
听着  我...我正准备打给你
Um, listen, I was -- I was planning on calling you.
是吗  那我来了
Really? Well, here I am.
粗狂帅气  任你差遣
Roguishly handsome and at your service.
你有何需要
What do you need?
我只是想稍后回公寓一趟
Um, I was just hoping I could stop by the loft later on
把剩下东西打包带走
'cause I need to pick up the rest of my stuff.
当然  随时欢迎
Uh, absolutely. Yeah, anytime.
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
她显然喜欢你
She's clearly got the hots for you.
谁
Who?
辣妹警监啊
Captain hoochie mama.
她看到你的时候  信息素分泌都要冲破天际了
Her pheromone output went through the roof when she saw you.
你怎么知道的
And you know this how?
我能闻到  就像我还能闻到
I can smell it, like I can smell
你今早用剃须膏洗了头
that you washed your hair with shaving cream this morning,
而且你吃了隔夜的玉米饼却没刷牙
And you chose day-old tacos over brushing your teeth.
你是巫师吗
Are you a wizard?
被诅咒的巫师
A cursed one.
等等  你有嗅觉过敏症
Wait. You have hyperosmia.
你的嗅觉到底敏感到了什么程度
Just how heightened is your olfactory acuity?
超级敏感  你怎么...
It's off the charts. How do you --
我博览群书啊
I read a lot.
你是说
You're telling me you can tell
你单凭贝克特散发出的气味就能知道她对我的感觉
exactly how Beckett feels about me just by her smell?
没错
Yes.
告诉你吧
Tell you what.
我有辆新款法拉利就在楼下
I have a brand-new ferrari downstairs.
闻起来就像天堂
Smells like heaven.
要不我送你回家
How about I give you a ride home
你再跟我多说说
and you can tell me a little more?
或者让朱利安警官送你也行
Or officer Julian here can give you a ride home,
他最爱的食物可是香肠配巧克力奶
and his favorite meal is sausages and chocolate milk.
这就对了
That's what I thought.
朱利安  交给我就行了  谢了
Julian, I got this. Thanks.
海莉  你怎么来了
Hayley, what are you doing here?
工作
Working.
她也很喜欢我  你应该能...
She likes me a lot, too. You can probably tell --
并没有
No.
我们还在查被害人的电话记录和社交网络信息
We're still looking into our victim's phone records and social media,
但目前为止  还没发现任何叫猎鹰的
But so far, we haven't found anyone named Falcon.
但我们发现了一条可能的线索
But we did find a possible link
是一家叫猎鹰会的公司
to a company called the Falcon Unit.
现在正在查
We're checking them out now.
还费什么劲  我知道他们啊
Why bother when I could just tell you who they are?
某人真会隆重登场
Somebody knows how to make an entrance.
大家好啊
Hello, all.
你好啊姑娘  还好吗
What's up, girl? How you doing?
很高兴再次见到你  裤子真赞
Nice to see you again. Great pants.
言归正传  你刚才说...
Anyway, you were saying?
猎鹰会  这是家私人公司
The Falcon Unit, it's a private company
特长是帮富有的客户
that specializes in transporting sensitive
运输敏感的  偶尔还有违法的物品
and occasionally illegal items for wealthy clients.
那咱们的被害人是像电影里那种送玩命快递的
So our victim was a transporter, like the movie?
这就解释了装甲的跑车
That explains the armored sports car
和秘密隔间
and secret compartment.
那么  公文包里有什么
So, what was in the briefcase?
恐怕答案是有偿的
I'm afraid the answer to that comes with a price.
我想加入调查
I want in on the investigation.
这事对你有什么好处
And what's in this for you?
公文包里的物品
The item in the briefcase
保了很大一笔保险
has a rather large insurance policy.
保险公司雇我把它找回来
The insurance company has hired me to recover it.
这可不是什么寻宝游戏
You know, this isn't a treasure hunt.
我们是要破凶杀案
We're trying to solve a homicide.
死者是因为那个箱子而死的
And your victim was killed for that briefcase,
如果你找到凶手  我也能找到丢失的东西
so you find your killer, I find my missing item.
大家各取所需
Everyone goes home happy?
好吧
Okay.
那死者要运送的是什么东西
So, what was our victim hired to transport?
一副梵高的画  在二战时丢失了
A Van Gogh, lost since World War II,
在三周前的拍卖会上以六千五百万被拍下
purchased at auction 3 weeks ago for $65 million.
丢失很久的梵高的画卖出了大价钱
Long-lost Van Gogh sold for a fortune.
这事网上怎么没有
How come this wasn't on the Internet?
这幅画的身世很复杂
The painting has a complicated history.
在战争期间被抢过很多次
It was looted several times during the war,
想要正当买卖是不可能的
which made an aboveboard sale impossible,
所以只能秘密地在苏黎世被拍卖
so it was auctioned secretly in Zurich,
买家远程竞拍
with potential buyers bidding remotely.
我们应该弄到竞拍者的名单
We should get a list of the other bidders.
可能是其中一个没拍到的人想要偷它
Maybe one of the losers tried to steal it.
我已经试过了  拍卖行不合作
I already tried. Auction house isn't playing ball.
如果他们泄露了客户资料
I mean, they give up their clients,
他们的生意就完了
they lose their business.
我去联系一下国务院
You know what? I'll reach out to the state department,
看他们能不能施加点压力
see if they can apply a little pressure.
我想我找到凶手了
I think I found our killer.
一部自动取款机的摄像头
An ATM camera caught a guy
拍下了一个符合目击者描述的人
matching our witness' description
在十点半的时候离开了停车场
exiting the parking garage at 10:30.
那是凶案发生后十五分钟
That's 15 minutes after the murder.
他怎么还在附近呢
How come he was still around?
可能是藏箱子
Probably stashing the briefcase.
两分钟后  一个地铁的摄像头拍到了他
Two minutes later, a subway cam caught him
正在上F线
hopping the "F" Train.
他的地铁卡是用一张信用卡买的
Now, his metro card was purchased with a credit card
卡主是弗雷迪·斯塔克  一个低级的混混
belonging to a Freddy Stark, a low-level dirtbag
有过非法闯入和暴力袭击的前科
with a history of B&E and violent assault.
干得漂亮  警长
Nice job, Sarge.
贝克特和我结婚将近一年了
So, Beckett and I had been married almost a year,
而且我们之间挺好的
And -- and things were going great,
可是突然之间  她就说需要空间
and then, suddenly, she says she needs space.
这关我什么事呢
Why is that my problem?
不关的  我只是在想
Oh, it's not, but I-I was just thinking,
你对信息素那么敏感
you're so attuned to pheromone output,
这样你就能在贝克特的事上帮到我
you could help me with my interactions with Beckett,
告诉我什么时候吸引到她了
let me know when I'm being charming,
什么时候烦到她了
let me know when I'm annoying her.
像这样吗
You mean like this?
卡塞尔  你很烦人
Hey, Castle, you're being annoying.
是的  不过我觉得
Yes, only I'm thinking
最好是悄悄地给我做个手势  这样她就...
more like a secret hand gesture so she doesn't...
你是说现在我很烦人吗
You mean right now?
是的
Yeah.
听着  你其实在气味上没特别恼人
Listen, you are actually fairly inoffensive on an odor level,
可是我不喜欢与人交际
but I am not a people person
而且我也不想跟人交际
and have zero interest in becoming one.
让我进去  我会说服你的
Let me in. Let me convince you.
想都别想  除了我没人能进去
Forget it. No one goes inside but me.
这样会很寂寞啊
Well, that sounds lonely.
才不会
It's not.
不  我才不...
No. I-I-I'm not...
就五分钟
Five minutes.
如果我说服不了你
If I haven't convinced you,
你可以把我赶出来
you can just kick me out.
好吧
Fine.
可是你得先净化一下
But you have to be decontaminated.
挺好玩的啊
Sounds like fun.
你在家里工作
You work from home.
我给一家香水公司做气味顾问
I consult for a perfume company as a professional nose,
专攻原始吸引
specializing in primal attraction.
可你一个人住  也没有人来看你
And yet you live alone and never have visitors.
我也见人的
I see people.
每周去一次办公室
I go into the office once a week.
我只能承受这么多
That's all I can handle.
况且  看我离开家发生了什么
And besides, look what happens when you leave.
搭电梯的时候遇到一个满头大汗的凶手
You wind up riding an elevator with a sweaty killer.
你能闻到他出汗了
You could smell his sweat.
还有他的枪
And his gun.
还有什么
What else?
没了
Nothing.
扯  你就像条猎犬
Bull. You're like a bloodhound.
你只是不想被牵扯到其中
You just don't want to get involved.
可是我敢打赌  只要你再闻到这个凶手
But I'm betting you could identify this killer
你就能认出他来
if you smelled him again.
很好闻
That's nice.
-你喜欢艺术吗  弗雷迪  -我喜欢漫画书
- You an art fan, Freddy? - I like comic books.
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
-那梵高呢  -从没听说过
- How about Van Gogh? - I never heard of him.
今天早晨十点一刻你在哪里
Where were you at 10:15 this morning?
我在上城区  溜我的猫
I was uptown, walking my cat.
可是我们有证据显示你在东格林威治
And yet we have proof that you were in the East Village,
杀人
committing a homicide.
不可能
Never happened.
我的猫不喜欢那里
My cat hates the East Village.
警监
Captain?
是卡塞尔  他来电话了
It's castle. He's on the phone.
-他说案子有突破口了  -什么案子
- He says he's got a break in the case. - What case?
这个案子吗
This case?
他怎么知道这个案子的
How does he even know about this case?
哪能这么跟可以认出
Now, is that any way to talk to the man
凶手的人说话
who can I.D. your killer?
等一下  你能认出他吗
Wait. You can I.D. Him?
-我不行  不过米娅可以  -我认不出
- Well, no, but Mia can. - No, I can't.
谁是米娅
Who's Mia?
她是目击证人
She's an eyewitness --
准确地说  她是鼻击证人
Well, technically, she's a nose-witness.
请把那个放下
Please put that down.
她跟凶手搭了同一部电梯
She shared an elevator with our killer,
可凶手带着面具
who was wearing a mask.
无所谓  因为她能通过味道认出他来
That doesn't matter because she can I.D. him by his smell.
是的  她说他闻起来像是火药味
Yeah, she said that he smelled like gunpowder.
我要挂电话了
Look, I'm gonna hang up.
这可不是瞎闹的时候
This isn't time for party games.
没有瞎闹
It's not a party game.
好吧  那你就告诉我们点
Okay, then tell us something unique
-凶手气味的特别之处  -是啊
- about the killer's scent. - Yeah.
有一丝卸甲油的味道
There was a hint of nail-polish remover.
一个一米八的人身上有卸甲油的味道吗
A six-foot-tall guy who smells like nail-polish remover.
这是在浪费时间
This is a waste of time.
等等  告诉她那个
Hang on. Tell her the thing.
好吧  这个怎么样
Okay, how about this?
那个手提箱里面有一副老油画
There was an old oil painting in that briefcase.
信了吧
Boom.
你怎么知道这个的
How do you know that?
你反应迟钝吗  我闻见了
Are you slow? I smelled it.
你确定你想挽回她吗
Are you sure you want her back?
我觉得你能找到更好的
'cause I think you can do better.
-这  -贝克特  我们马上去分局
- This - Beckett, we're gonna come down to the precinct.
不  卡塞尔
No! Castle --
我不去
I'm not going.
不  你要去
Yes, you are.
为什么  因为你觉得我能帮你挽回你妻子
Why? Because you think I can help you get your wife back?
不  好吧  是
No. Well, y-yes.
但也是因为今天早上有一个人被谋杀了
But because a man was murdered this morning,
需要有人为他伸张正义
and that man deserves justice.
你把你的嗅觉过敏当作诅咒
You know, you see your hyperosmia as a curse,
但与此同时  你也获得了一个很好的天赋
when, really, you've been given a great gift.
在你的帮助下
And with your help,
警察可以把这个冷血杀手抓捕归案
the police can put away a cold-blooded killer.
这是不是值得让你出面帮忙
Now, isn't that worth putting yourself out there?
不
No.
你做什么也不能
And there is nothing you can do
让我离开我的公寓
to make me leave my apartment.
什么都不能
Nothing?
Nothing.
-抱歉  -天啊
- I'm sorry. - Oh, my god.
特殊情况  特殊手段
Desperate times call for desperate measures.
这些玉米片味道真难闻
Oh, you were right about those tacos.
他不是凶手
He's not the killer.
如果被别人知道我授权闻味指认凶手
If word gets out that I authorized a smell lineup --
有让见到过凶手的人看人指认
They have visual lineups for people who have seen killers,
听过凶手说话的人通过声音指认
Voice lineups for people who have heard them.
但无论如何  我们知道弗雷迪当时在停车场
But regardless, we know Freddy was at the garage,
他很明显在说谎  所以
and he's clearly lying, so --
我们骗他  告诉他我们的目击者已经指认他了
So we lie to him, tell him that our witness I.D.'d him.
然后看他说什么
And watch him talk.
我没杀他
I didn't kill him!
我们的目击者可不是这么说的
That's not what our witness says.
这算什么指认啊
What kind of lineup was that, anyway?
那个目击者都没有看我的脸
The witness didn't even look at my face!
-那幅画在哪  -不在我这
- Where's the painting? - I don't have it.
别废话  弗雷迪
Cut the crap, Freddy.
你只有一次机会说服我
You got one chance to convince me
你不是杀人犯
that you're not the murderer.
好吧  听着  我确实在停车场
Okay, listen, I was at the garage,
但不是去杀人的
but not to kill the guy.
-我被派去取回那幅画  -谁派你的
- I was hired to retrieve the painting. - By who?
汤姆·吉列姆  猎鹰会的头
Tom Gilliam. Head of the falcon unit.
就是让贾斯汀去运送那幅画的公司
That's who hired Justin to transport it.
他们为什么又会让你去偷
Why would they want you to steal it from him?
我不知道
I don't know.
但吉列姆让我去
But Gilliam was really upset
找贾斯汀时非常不高兴
when he hired me to hunt Justin down,
叫我无论如何都要把画拿回来
told me to do whatever it took to get the painting back.
所以我黑了贾斯汀车上的导航
So I hacked the GPS in justin's car
跟踪他去了停车场
and followed him to the garage.
但等我赶到时
But by the time I got there,
他已经死了  画也不见了
he was already dead and the painting was gone.
你什么时候赶到停车场的
What time did you get there?
十点二十才到
Didn't get to the garage till 10:20.
好吧  谢谢
All right, thanks.
警监证实了弗雷迪的说法
Captain confirms Freddy's story.
所以他在米娅报警后才到
So he arrived after Mia called 911.
意味着他不是凶手
Which means he ain't our guy.
你打算怎么审这个猎鹰会的家伙
So, how do you want to go at this falcon unit dude?
我说我们跟他来硬的
I say we hit him hard.
这种人只有恐吓他才能起作用
Guys like this only respond to intimidation.
现在要这样了吗
Is that the way it's gonna be now?
我升职了  所以我说我们这么做
"I get this big promotion, and I say we do it this way."
不  我们可以按照你的方式来
Hey, hey, no. We can do it your way.
你想怎么做
How do you want to play it?
我说我们跟他来硬的
I say we go at him hard.
打扰了
Excuse me!
汤姆·吉列姆  我是莱恩警探
Tom Gilliam, I'm detective Ryan.
这是埃斯波西托警探
This is detective Esposito.
关于贾斯汀·弗莱彻的凶杀案
We just have a few questions
我们有几个问题要问你
about the murder of Justin Fletcher.
那真是个悲剧  但我对此一无所知
A real tragedy, but I don't know anything about it.
那就有意思了  因为弗雷迪·斯塔克说你知道
That's funny, 'cause Freddy Stark says you do.
有什么我能帮忙的吗
How can I help you?
你可以从告诉我们为什么你雇佣弗雷迪
Well, you can start by telling us why you hired Freddy
去从你自己的雇员那把画偷回来开始
to steal that painting back from your own employee.
你们消息错了
You got it all wrong.
我没有雇佣弗雷迪去偷它
I didn't hire Freddy to steal it.
我雇佣他去取回它
I hired him to retrieve it.
贾斯汀从我们这偷走了它
Justin stole it from us.
这说不通
That doesn't make sense.
你雇佣贾斯汀来运输这幅画
You hired Justin to transport the painting.
不  我雇佣了别人
No. I hired someone else.
运输货物的人抽取佣金  货到付款
Transporters work on commission, payable upon delivery,
那幅画的佣金达到了六位数
and the commission for that painting was six figures.
贾斯汀一定是起了贪心  抢了这份工作
Justin must have gotten greedy and jumped the job.
直到真的运输员来取那幅画的时候
We didn't realize until the real transporter arrived
我们才意识到它不见了
to pick up the painting, and it was gone.
那谁是真正的运输员
Then who's the real transporter?
利亚姆·霍利斯特  前英国雇佣兵
Liam Hollister, ex-British mercenary.
因为太过暴力被开除出
Kicked out of the French foreign legion
法国外籍兵团
for being too violent.
根据海莉的说法
According to Hayley,
猎鹰每当有大笔的业务时都会找利亚姆
Liam is falcon's go-to guy for big-money jobs.
我认为他对于贾斯汀偷走他的任务
I don't think he'd take too kindly
不会很高兴
to Justin stealing his commission.
可能采取了擅自行动
Might go rogue.
于是他跟踪贾斯汀去了那个停车场
So he tracked Justin to that garage
用两颗子弹交换了那幅画
and traded two bullets for that painting.
按说他刚杀了人
You'd think he'd be rolling around in something
该开辆低调点的车出来晃
a little more subtle after committing murder.
是啊
Yeah.
兄弟  我们没事吧
Hey, bro... are we good?
是啊  当然
Yeah, yeah. Of course.
为什么这么问
Why do you even ask?
因为你一整天都有点奇怪
Cause you've been acting weird all day.
我知道你很失望
And I know that you're bummed,
但是你甚至都没有恭喜我通过了
But you never even gave me props for passing.
哈维  你说得对
Yeah. Javi, you're right, man.
恭喜  兄弟  真的
Congratulations, man. Really.
谢谢
Thanks, bro.
他来了
Here we go.
你去左边
Go left.
哈维  你没事吧
Javi, you okay?
有事  你打中我屁股了
No! You shot me in the ass!
-你打伤了你的搭档  -在屁股上
- You shot your partner. - In the ass.
纯属意外
It was an accident.
医生说他没事的
The hospital says he's gonna be fine.
只要缝几针就好了
Just needs a few stitches.
还得要一条新裤子
And a new pair of trousers.
有利亚姆的消息吗
Any sign of Liam?
没有  但他是开着劳斯菜斯逃跑的
No, but he fled in his Rolls,
所以我们让维克拉姆监控了
so we've got Vikram monitoring every street cam
城里每个十字路口的监控
at every crossing in the city,
只要他试图离开曼哈顿
which means if he tries to get out of Manhattan,
我们就能找到他
we will find him.
那我去配合他
Well, I will coordinate with him,
查一下利亚姆的生活
start digging into Liam's life,
看能不能找出他的藏身之处
try and figure out where he might go to ground.
你知道利亚姆会丢弃那辆车对吧
You know Liam's gonna ditch the car, right?
我知道
I know.
像那样的车肯定能换个好价钱
A ride like that would fetch top dollar.
如果利亚姆要逃跑他可能会想快点拿到钱
If Liam's bolting, he might want some quick cash.
你要给谁打电话
Who are you calling?
你丈夫
Your husband.
我想他应该有朋友知道
I reckon that he might have some friends
在哪里能迅速把一辆劳斯莱斯卖掉
who would know where to sell a hot rolls in a hurry.
你还在这干嘛
Why are you still here?
案子还没结呢
The case isn't over yet.
但已经不管我的事了
It is for me.
我看到你在分局
I saw you back at the precinct.
你还挺开心的
You were having fun.
不  我没有
No, I wasn't.
理查德·卡塞尔
Richard Castle.
我会问问的  好的
I'll ask around. Okay.
好了  我们有了新任务
All right, we have a new mission --
找出嫌疑人
To find where our suspect
可能会在哪卖掉高档的劳斯莱斯
might sell a high-end Rolls-Royce.
这我可帮不了你
I can't help you with that.
但我们一到那你就可以指认他
But you can I.D. him once we get there.
你为什么要这么对我
Why are you doing this to me?
因为你帮了我  我现在得报答你
Because you helped me out, and now I'm returning the favor.
通过折磨我吗
By torturing me?
不是的
No.
米娅  你这样不算生活
Mia, you're -- you're not living.
你在逃避
You're hiding.
我知道你觉得这个世界有点让你承受不来
I know you find the world a little overwhelming,
但在外面  才是真正的生活
But out here, this is where life happens.
所以  我们走吧
So...let's go.
搭档  让我帮你
Hey, partner, let me help you with that.
我自己可以
I can handle it myself.
哈维  那是个意外
Javi, it was an accident.
你怎么来了  快回家吧
Hey, what are you doing here? Go home.
不  我是来工作的
No. I'm here to work.
-但你受伤了  -皮外伤而已
- But you were shot. - It's just a flesh wound.
如果他在工作  那我也要工作
If he's working, then I'm working.
我刚查到利亚姆的通话记录
So, I just got Liam's phone records.
不到一小时前他联系了霍桑·卡特
He called Hawthorne Carter less than half an hour ago.
这个名字怎么听起来这么熟
Why is that name so familiar?
他是个对冲基金的亿万富翁
He's a hedge-fund billionaire whose hobbies include
兴趣包括世界争霸游戏以及艺术收藏
World Domination and art collection.
告诉他  想让我卖
Tell him the only way I'll sell
除非他等我下来  让我给他脸上来一拳
is if he lets me come down and punch him in the face.
不  窗帘很好看
No, the drapes are great.
卡特先生  你得把电话挂掉
Mr. Carter, you need to get off the phones.
立刻
Now.
好吧  待会回给你
Fine. I'll call you back.
请把两部电话都挂掉
Both phones, please.
再见
Goodbye.
坐下
Sit down
否则我将以共谋谋杀的罪名逮捕你
or I will arrest you for conspiracy to commit murder.
洛伦佐  她在说什么
Lorenzo, what is she talking about?
梵高的那幅画  先生
The Van Gogh, sir.
三周前你在拍卖会竞拍那幅画  没拍到
Three weeks ago, you bid on it at an auction, and you lost.
今天早上  那幅画被偷了
This morning, it was stolen,
一个男人被枪击而死
And a man was found shot to death.
卡特先生今天下午才从新加坡回来
Mr. Carter just got back from Singapore this afternoon.
不是这意思  我们知道不是你杀了他
No, we don't think you killed him.
但你却和凶手有联系
But you are in contact with the man who did.
利亚姆·霍利斯特  护送画的人
Liam Hollister, the transporter.
据猎鹰会所说
According to the Falcon Unit,
你雇过他很多次
you've engaged his services numerous times.
是的  他打电话说出手那幅画
Yeah. He called, looking to unload the painting.
我把画拍下只是因为洛伦佐觉得
I only bid on it 'cause Lorenzo thought
那画挂在我的私人飞机里很好看
it would look great hanging in my g5.
-你没同意买下那幅画吗  -当然
- So you're saying you didn't agree to buy it? - Hell no!
我已经买了幅杰克逊·波洛克的作品挂那
I already bought a Jackson Pollock to hang in there.
你知道他现在在哪吗
Do you have any idea where he is now?
没有  当我不同意买画时
Nope, but when I said no to the painting,
他问我是否对一辆二手劳斯莱斯有兴趣
he asked if I had any interest in a used Rolls-Royce.
先生  有什么我能帮你的吗
Yes, sir? How can I help you?
是的  蒙蒂让我来的
Yes. Uh... Monty sent me.
我明白了
I see.
你的法拉利被偷了吗
So your Ferrari was stolen?
是的  恐怕我那可怜的保险公司
Yes, and I'm afraid my poor insurance company
报案后得付一大笔钱了
is going to have to pay out a fortune when I report it.
我想看看我还能多挣多少
Now, how much extra can I look forward to making?
我得去查一下
Well, gonna have to run some numbers,
但我得看看外国买家愿意出多少
but I'll see what our foreign buyers might pay for it.
谢谢
Thank you.
那辆看上去像利亚姆的车
Right. That looks like Liam's car right there.
去看看
Let's go.
爱死这车
Love it.
想要这车
Want it.
需要这车
Need it.
敞篷车  太恶心了
Uh. Convertible -- yuck.
好了  你去把后备箱开一下好吗
All right, why don't you, uh, pop the trunk?
好的
O-okay.
你在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
只是看看这辆车而已
Oh! Just taking a look at the car.
-走开  -没问题
- Yeah, back up. - Hey, no problem.
好的
Yes.
快点出来
Hey! Get out of there!
用不着这样
No need for that.
米娅
Mia!
我干得不错吧
Did I do okay?
简直完美
You did perfectly!
我认输了
I give up.
你们俩怎么把利亚姆困在他的后备箱里
How the hell did the two of you trap Liam in his own trunk?
因为我俩很棒你俩太逊  下个问题
Because we're awesome and you two suck. Next question.
你怎么了
What -- what happened to you?!
执行任务时受伤了
Injured in the line of duty.
真的吗  怎么搞的
Really? How?
我  不小心冲他开了一枪
I... accidentally shot him
打到了臀大肌
in the gluteus maximus.
屁股上
In the ass?!
或许我应该把这个交给你
Well, maybe I should give this to you.
抱歉  这没什么好笑的
I'm sorry. This is so not funny.
没错  简直太搞笑了
You're right. It's hilarious.
笑死人了
It's hilarious!
来吧  米娅  我们把这儿交给
Come on, Mia. Let's make way for, uh,
神枪手莱恩和埃斯波西臀
Crack-shot Ryan and Assposito.
埃斯波西臀
"Assposito."
利亚姆  纽约警察
Liam, NYPD.
我们现在要打开后备箱  别做傻事
We're about to open this trunk, so don't do anything stupid.
不是我干的
It wasn't me!
我猜不是你拿了那个装着被盗画作的
So I guess it wasn't you who had the stolen painting
银色箱子
in the silver briefcase.
我猜也不是你
I suppose it also wasn't you
试图在那座大楼里杀掉我们
who tried to kill us in that building.
相信我  如果我想杀你们  你们早死了
Oh, trust me, if I was trying to kill you, you'd be dead.
我只是开火压制你们  好让自己脱身
Wow. I was laying down a suppressive fire in order to get away.
我故意射偏的  不像你  朋友
I aimed to miss, unlike you, mate,
你开枪打了自己搭档的屁股
who shot your own partner in the ass.
好了  不  不要再考虑我们的事
Okay, l-let's not concern ourselves
包括谁射伤了  埃斯波西臀  托
with who shot Detective Assp-- Es--
埃斯波西托警探
Espo-- Eetective Esposito.
坐下  立刻  坐下否则我把你关起来
Sit down now! Sit down or I'm locking you up!
坐下了
Over there.
不如  我们讨论一下你是怎么枪杀了贾斯汀
Rather, let's discuss how you shot Justin.
告诉你了  不是我干的
I'm telling you it wasn't me.
我明白  你被激怒了
Look, I get it. You were pissed.
他在你护送活儿里插了一脚
He jumped you on that transporter job,
把你踢出了一单大生意
screwed you out of a big commission.
于是你找到他
And then you tracked him down,
在停车场跟他对质
and you confronted him in that garage.
你大概本来没想杀人
You probably didn't even mean to kill.
我没有杀贾斯汀
I didn't shoot Justin.
废话少说
Cut that crap.
所有证据都指向你
All the evidence points to you.
所以我才要躲着你们
Which is why I ran from you guys.
听着  我当时在那个停车场里
Look, I was at that parking garage,
但是我离开的时候  贾斯汀还活着
but when I left, Justin was alive.
像你说的那样
It's like you said,
我找贾斯汀对质  他道歉了
I confronted Justin, but he apologized.
他知道对不起我
He knew he did me wrong,
所以他把画还给我了  然后我离开了
so he gave me back the painting, and I left.
一定是有人在我走之后杀了他
And someone else must have come after me and shot him.
你真的指望我们相信
Do you really expect us to believe that?
不
No.
但这是事实
But it's the truth.
这个案子针对利亚姆的证据都是间接的
This case against Liam is pretty circumstantial.
希望弹道检测能证实
Well, hopefully, ballistics can match
他的枪是凶器
his gun to the murder weapon.
我需要吃的  马上
I need food now.
你们要知道  在饿肚子的时候
And just so you know, when hungry,
我会有易怒倾向
I do have a tendency to become irritable.
你易怒  我才不信呢
You irritable? I don't believe it.
美极了  不是吗
Beautiful, isn't it?
需要多久才能让我把它送回我的雇主那
How long before I can return it to my employer?
这个得检察官说了算
Well, that's up to the D.A.
这是个赝品  你知道的吧
It's a forgery, you know?
-什么  -你怎么知道
- What? - How do you know?
你能闻出来
You can smell it.
油画需要很多年才能完全干燥
Oil paint takes many years to become fully dry.
这幅闻起来太新鲜了  不可能是19世纪的
That smells way too fresh to be from the 19th century.
这幅绝对不是杀手
That's definitely not the painting
箱子里的那幅画
that was in the killer's briefcase.
难道利亚姆说的是真的
Maybe Liam was telling the truth?
如说是真的  那就能解释
If he was, it would explain
为什么贾斯汀那么轻易就放弃了这幅画
why Justin gave up the painting so easily.
他知道这是赝品
He knew it was a fake.
那就意味着真正的凶手还拿着那副真的画
Which means the real killer is still out there,
逍遥法外
with the real painting.
我爱死剧情反转了
Oh, I love it when there's a twist.
我爱死肚子饱饱的了
And I love it when my belly's full.
我  我这就订外卖
I-I'm getting takeout right now.
餐厅食品
Restaurant food?
绝不
Hell no!
我只吃家里做的饭
Home cooking only.
所有食物必须用蒸的而且没有
Everything has to be steamed with zero --
我是说完全没有  任何调味料
and I mean zero -- seasoning.
如果让我闻到或者看到一粒盐
If I even smell or see a speck of salt,
有人会受伤的
somebody is gonna get hurt.
你是我的司机  卡塞尔  我们走
You're my ride, Castle. Let's go.
祝你好胃口  亲爱的
Bon appetit, babe.
拜托
Man.
米娅  如果你想要清淡没味的食物
Mia, if you have a hankering for a bland meal,
我要推荐你  我母亲做的菜
I have a treat for you -- my mother's cooking.
我听见了  理查德
I heard that, Richard.
我想你态度应该好一点
I think gratitude would be appropriate,
好歹我在给你蒸这顿奇怪的饭
Since I am steaming this ridiculous meal for you.
玛莎·罗杰斯
Martha Rodgers.
是我
Yes.
抱歉  我们之前见过吗
I'm sorry. Have we met?
1999年5月19日
Uh, May 19, 1999.
我看过你在《彼平正传》的演出
I saw you perform in "Pippin."
我的天啊  你记得吗
Oh, my go-- you remember that?
没错  小百老汇
Oh, yeah. Off-Off-Broadway.
母亲  那可是在新泽西
Uh, mother, that was New Jersey.
所以我说的是小百老汇嘛
Off-Off-Broadway, as I said.
这真好啊
Well, isn't this nice?
你喜欢我们的剧
So you liked the production?
不  我讨厌它
No. Hated it.
另外  那个剧场闻起来好像
Plus, the theater smelled like
炎热夏天存放的比利时干酪肉汤
limburger gravy on a hot summer's day.
不过你  你棒极了
But you -- you were amazing.
真的吗  你一整天和这位畅销作家一起  无感
Really? So all day with a best-selling author, nothing.
和我妈在一起20秒
20 seconds with my mother,
你就变成泰勒·斯威夫特演唱会上的小女生了
You're a tweener at a Taylor Swift concert?
别乱喷  理查德
Don't be a hater, Richard.
这就是戏剧的魅力
It's the power of theater.
继续  慢慢说  你有点太激动了
Go on, go on. You were raving.
你的表演  太感人了
Your performance -- it was so moving.
让我完全忘记了我的真实生活有多糟糕
I completely forgot how horrible my real life was.
那简直  那是最美好的一天
It was just -- it was the best day ever.
亲爱的
Oh! Sweetheart.
而且你几乎没有臭味
Oh! And you barely stink. Oh!
从她嘴里说出来  这是非常高的评价
Oh, coming from her, that's high praise.
贝克特  我查到一些东西
Hey, Beckett, I got something.
是我们查到一些东西
We've got something.
没错  我正是这么说的
Yeah, that's what I said.
-你不是那么说的  -好吧  但我就那个意思
- That's not what you said. - Okay, it's what I meant.
好吧  你们只要有一个人告诉我到底是什么事
Okay, you both get gold stars for the day
我今天就给你们俩都发小红花
if just one of you can tell me what's going on.
我们查了一下
We did some digging
这幅油画痛苦的历史
into this painting's tortured history.
第二次世界大战时被盗
Stolen during World War II.
被拍卖前
It ended up in a private collection
是私人收藏
before coming up for auction.
显然  这种被盗的艺术品
Apparently, stolen artwork like this
很难回到主人的手中
rarely ends up in the hands of its owner.
这跟贾斯汀的谋杀案有什么关系
What does any of this have to do with Justin's murder?
大有联系
Everything.
这幅梵高跟我们认识的一个人有关
The Van Gogh is connected to somebody we know.
-谁  -两年前  丢失这幅画的那家人
- Who? - Two years ago, there was a failed legal claim
提起了法律诉讼  却以失败告终
on behalf of the family that the painting was stolen from.
猜猜这家人是谁
And guess who filed it.
你还想吃真是太好了
Oh, so glad you wanted a second helping.
谢谢  玛莎  太美味了
Thank you, Martha. It's perfect.
我想我的味觉都睡着了
I think my palate fell asleep.
那是给咱俩叫的外卖
Oh. That will be the takeout for you and me.
干得漂亮
Well done.
你
Hel--
妈  你到底点了什么
Mother, what exactly did you order?
卡塞尔先生  你要跟我走一趟
Mr. Castle, you're coming with me.
不  他才不会跟你走
Oh, no, he is not.
妈  没事  没事
Oh, mother, it's -- it's all right.
好吧  你是谁
Okay, so, uh, who are you?
我是谁不重要
Who I am's not important.
你是谁才重要
It's who you are that is.
你娶了十二区分局的警监
You're married to the captain of the 12th precinct,
现在有一幅艺术品正保存在那里
where a certain work of art is being held.
你要去替我拿回来
You're going to go and get it for me.
给我一个这么做的理由
Give me one good reason why I should.
我给你两个
I'll give you two.
天啊
Oh! Oh, my God!
好吧  好吧  你把枪指回我
Okay, okay. Put -- put the gun back -- back to me.
-指着我就好了  -那幅画是属于我们家的
- Point it at me. - Look, that painting belongs to my family.
我父亲终其一生在寻找它
My father spent his life trying to find it.
他去世的时候心已碎
He died a broken man.
我绝不可能让它
There's no way I'm going to let it
落在某个亿万富豪的窝里
sit in some billionaire's man cave.
好的  我明白  真的
Okay, I get it. I do.
说真的  我也想帮你
And I want to help you, honestly.
但是即使我愿意  我也拿不到那幅画
But I can't get that painting even if I tried.
为什么
And why is that?
露西不会让我那么做的
Lucy's not gonna let me.
谁他妈的是露西
Who the hell's Lucy?
她就在你身后
She's right behind you.
准确的说  我在他左边
Technically, I am to his left.
你们看到没  我一拳就把他干掉了
Did you see that?! Knocked him out with one punch!
被干掉的不只他一个人
And he wasn't the only one.
里克  你还好吧
Rick, are you okay?
一点也不好
Far from it.
我想米娅要告我们
I think Mia is gonna sue us
让我们赔个倾家荡产
for everything we've got.
那是  他打断了我挣钱的家伙
Yeah. He broke my money-maker.
我道过歉了
I said I was sorry.
还有个坏消息
Well, uh, there's more bad news.
洛伦佐不是凶手  我跟他的同事谈过
Lorenzo's not our killer. I spoke with his co-workers.
他的不在场证明很牢靠
He's got a rock-solid alibi.
这很合理
Well, that makes sense.
他要是愿意杀贾斯汀的话
If he was willing to kill Justin,
那幅梵高早就到他手上了
he'd already have the Van Gogh
他也就不用让我去偷那幅赝品了
and he wouldn't have asked me to steal the fake one.
等一下  你们找到的梵高是那幅赝品
Hold on. The Van Gogh you recovered is the forgery?
你是怎么知道赝品的事的
How do you know about the forgery?
洛伦佐  你现在麻烦大着呢
Lorenzo, you are in a world of trouble.
你现在最好把你知道的一切都告诉我们
Your best bet is to tell us everything you know now.
我整个成年时光
I have spent my entire adult life
都在找寻那幅画
searching for that painting.
当我听说它要被拍卖时
When I heard it was coming up for auction,
我就试图让我老板买下它
I tried to get my boss to buy it.
但他不肯
But he wouldn't.
是的  但是我在贾斯汀送货时结识了他
No, but I knew Justin from some of his deliveries.
我做了点功课  发现在那幅画被转移前
I did some research, learned that we had three weeks
我们有三周的时间
before the painting was to be moved,
于是我们就秘密策划
so we hatched a plan.
让贾斯汀抢了利亚姆的护送工作
Justin would jump Liam's transporter job
然后用赝品把那幅梵高换出来
and switch the Van Gogh with the fake.
而那幅赝品是由你负责提供的
And you provided the forgery?
不  从一开始贾斯汀就说他认识一个人
No, from the very beginning, Justin said he knew a guy.
所以他才去那个停车场
That's why he went to the parking garage --
去取那幅赝品
to pick up the forged painting.
制造赝品的那个人才是凶手
Whoever forged that painting is the killer.
他杀害贾斯汀为了得到梵高的真迹
He killed Justin for the real Van Gogh.
但是贾斯汀在停车场把假画给了利亚姆
But Justin gave Liam the fake in the parking garage.
没错  所以呢
Yeah, so?
所以说在利亚姆到达前  画就已经被掉包了
So, the exchange happened before Liam even arrived.
但那并不意味着凶手跑掉了
That doesn't mean the killer was gone.
他可能只是躲起来了
He could have just been hiding.
要是利亚姆正好在掉包的时候到的呢
What if Liam drove up just as the swap was taking place?
那凶手就只能藏起来
Then the killer would take cover.
没错  所以利亚姆拿着假画走了
Right. So Liam drives away with the forgery,
凶手出来  杀掉贾斯汀  拿走了真迹
killer comes back out, kills Justin for the real one.
有这个可能
That's a possibility.
那问题就是  我们怎么辨认这个神秘人呢
Then the question is, how do we identify this mystery man?
通过他的味道
By his smell.
好主意  卡塞尔
Well, that's a great idea, Castle,
不过你把干这事的鼻子给打断了
but you literally just broke the nose.
那就只能靠我们了
Well, then, it's up to us.
贾斯汀把车停在这里见那个造假的人
Justin parked here to meet with the forger,
也就是说利亚姆肯定是从那边开进来的
which means Liam must have driven in from over there.
所以凶手肯定从这里跑掉
So the killer must have headed away from here
以防被人看到
to avoid being spotted.
但是  楼梯间是最好的躲藏地点
But, you know, the stairwell's the best option,
可是远在另外一边
but that's on the opposite side.
米娅说凶手身上有卸甲水的味道
Mia said the killer smelled like nail-polish remover.
是的  这也太不寻常了
Yeah, which is unusual.
那是什么声音
What is that noise?
听上去像是一台
It sounds like an air-conditioning unit
快报废的空调设备
on its last legs.
-就是它了  -是什么
- That's it. - What's it?
卸甲水
Nail-polish remover.
卸甲水之所以有那样的味道
Smells like nail-polish remover
是因为它的主要成分  丙酮
because of its active ingredient, acetone.
空调设备泄露
Air-conditioning units leak.
准确地说是泄露氟利昂
Specifically, they leak freon.
氟利昂闻起来
Freon smells...
像丙酮
like acetone.
凶手一定就站在氟利昂泄露处的旁边
The killer must have been standing next to a freon leak.
他可能离这个柱子非常近
He probably squeezed up against this pillar,
所以才会有氟利昂沾到他身上
and that's how he got the freon transferred onto him.
而且  这个...
And, uh, this...
很可能就是他的头发
may very well be his hair.
我们有了凶手的DNA
We have the killer's DNA.
-多谢你能回来  格雷汉姆  -没什么
- Thanks for coming back in, Graham. - Not a problem.
听说我哥哥的案子有进展了
So, there was an update to my brother's case?
是的  贾斯汀
Yeah, uh... Justin.
你大学的学费是他支付的
Now, he paid your college tuition,
艺术学院  对不对
didn't he, at the art institute?
这和案子有什么关系吗
What's that have to do with anything?
我们听说你是个出色的画家
Well, we heard that you were an amazing painter.
据你的教授所说  你很有天赋
Uh, gifted, according to your professors.
但却是个烂赌鬼
But a lousy gambler.
没错  我们核实过了
Yeah. We checked.
到处都有你的签名和借条
You had markers and I.O.U.s all over the city.
在地下赌场那种地方
At underground casinos -- the kind of establishments
他们是不会友善对待你这种还不起钱的人
that don't take kindly when you can't pay up.
我猜你哥哥让你伪造那幅梵高画的时候
I bet you thought it was your lucky day
你一定觉得自己遇到天大的好事了
when your brother asked you to forge that Van Gogh.
贾斯汀要卖掉那幅原画
Justin was gonna sell the original painting.
你们两个准备分掉所得的钱
The two of you would split the profits,
但当你发觉他准备
but when you found out that he was just gonna
把画送人  你有些生气了
give that painting away, you got a little pissed.
真荒唐
That's ridiculous.
这根本证明不了是我杀了他
I-it doesn't prove that I killed him, either.
的确  不过犯罪现场的头发可以证明
No, but the hair at the crime scene does.
我们检测了DNA
We ran the DNA.
跟你的哥哥有54%相似...
It's a match to your brother by 54%...
也就是说毛发属于他的兄弟姐妹
Also known as a sibling match.
你是个赌徒  对吧
Now, you're a gambling man, right?
如果我们检测这杯子上的毛发DNA
So how much do you want to bet that when we run that hair
你准备赌多少钱
against the DNA from this glass...
会是完全匹配
It's gonna be an exact match?
我们有你住处的搜查令
And we have a warrant for your place.
我们会在你那里找到什么呢
Now, what are we gonna find there?
你用的枪
The gun that you used?
还是那幅梵高的原画呢
The original Van Gogh?
他是我哥哥  我不想杀他的
H-he was my brother. I-I-I didn't want to kill him.
我只是  我需要钱
I just -- I-I needed the money.
你能看出区别来吗
So, can you tell the difference?
完全看不出来
Uh...no. Not at all.
我跟画作的现任主人谈过了
Oh, I, uh, spoke to the current owner,
把整件事都告诉了他  他表示
told him the whole story, and he pledged
只要洛伦佐家的案子一宣判
that he's going to give it to the State Museum
他就把这幅画献给国家博物馆
while Lorenzo's family's issue is being adjudicated.
所以  算是个好的结尾吧
So, bit of a happy ending.
很高兴跟你合作
Well, it was a pleasure working with you.
我也是
Yeah. You too.
身为警察  你是个好人
You're not so bad for a cop.
谢谢  你也是个好人  作为一个...
Thank you. You're not so bad for a-a...
你到底是做什么工作的
What -- what exactly do you do?
你需要帮忙吗
Hey, you need any help?
不劳烦你
Not from you.
哈维
Javi, look...
你能宽宏大量原谅我吗
...could you find it in your heart to forgive me?
好吧
All right.
我们没事了吗
We're cool?
是的
Yeah.
对不起
I'm sorry.
怎么  难道你不是故意的吗
What, like you didn't mean to do that?
那是个意外
Th-that was an accident!
似乎最近身边的意外
Well, it seems like there's been a lot of accidents
有点多啊  探长
around here lately, detective.
真的要这样吗
Oh. Oh, it's gonna be like that, Sarge?
好吧
Okay.
我们来扯平
Let's make it even then.
以眼还眼  以牙还牙
Eye for an eye, cheek for a cheek.
来报仇吧
Get your revenge, okay?
开枪打我屁股
Shoot me in the ass.
快点
Go. Now.
开枪打我屁股  打啊
Shoot me in the ass. Come on.
-现在就开枪  -老兄  起来
- Do it right now. - Hey, man. Get up.
赶紧动手吧  给个痛快的
Let's squash this right now! Just a quick pop!
-他在闹呢  -就打屁股上  快点
- He's -- he's playing. - Right in the butt, go!
你搞得我很难堪
You're embarrassing me.
别闹了
Knock it off!
-是他先... -知道吗
- Well, he started it with his -- - You know what?
如果你们俩私底下不能解决的话
If the two of you can't figure this out on your own,
那就去见心理医生  这是命令
then you're doing it in therapy, and that's an order --
什么借口都没有用
No ifs, ands, or buts.
我不是想双关
I didn't mean it like that.
你  你好
How -- hi.
你怎么样了  你的嗅觉怎么样了
How are you feeling -- or, rather, how are you smelling?
医生说肿消了
Oh, the doctor said my schnoz should go back to normal
我的鼻子就会康复的
once the swelling goes down.
是给我的吗
Those for me?
是的  是纸花  所以不会有香味的
Yeah. They're paper so you don't have to smell.
对之前的事我表示抱歉
I-I-I-I'm so sorry for everything.
真的不必
Don't. Come on.
昨天我做好些非常了不起的事
I did some pretty extraordinary things yesterday.
你说得对  我一直没好好生活过
And you were right. I haven't been living.
多亏了你  现在我会好好生活的
And thanks to you, now I will.
我觉得你会喜欢这个卡片的
Well, then, I think you're gonna like that card.
是我母亲新戏的票
It's a couple of tickets to my mother's new play.
米娅  我觉得你投入世界
Mia, I just think the world's a better place
会让它变得更好
with you running around in it.
知道吗  我闻不到你身上味道的时候
You know what? You're easier to be around
更好跟你相处
when I can't smell you.
谢谢
Thanks.
贝克特还爱你...
Beckett still loves you...
热烈得爱着你
With a passion,
而你不需要测量信息素也会感知得到
and you don't have to measure pheromones to sense that.
我的职业
I've spent my career
就是制造爱的香气...
manufacturing the aromas of love...
男士和女士的香水
for perfumes and colognes,
但那些都是伪造的
but they're all just forgeries...
就跟那幅画一样
like that painting.
而你和贝克特之间有的...
What you and Beckett have --
那才是最纯真的爱
Now that's the genuine article.
贝克特
Beckett?